(恰饭时间)本视频由Squarespace赞助，详情前往下方链接
This video was made possible by Squarespace. Build your website for 10% at squarespace.com/Wendover
17年前人类打破了一个航空界纪录
17 years ago, an aviation frontier was broken
2001年3月1日中午之前
Just before noon on March 1, 2001
一架波音777洲际客机从寒冷的纽约城河对岸纽瓦克机场起飞
a Continental Airlines 777 lifted off from frosty Newark Airport across the river from New York City
一路向北飞过美国、加拿大，过了北极变成了向南飞
It tracked north over the US, then Canada, then just kept flying north until north became south
然后飞过俄罗斯、蒙古、中国大陆
It flew south over Russia, then Mongolia, then mainland China
在16小时的飞行后降落在香港赤鱲角机场
before setting down at Chek Lap Kok Airport in Hong Kong after 16 hours
该航班因此成为世界上最长的航班
With that, there was a new longest flight in the world
两座城市之前从未有过直飞商业航班
The two cities had never before been connected by non-stop commercial flights
这在当时是一个里程碑式的成就
This was at the time a momentous achievement
所有频繁往返这两大经济中心的商务旅客都迫切希望该航班尽早开通
—all the business travelers making frequent trips between the two financial centers badly wanted this quicker flight
但你可能很奇怪这种航班怎么在21世纪才开通
—but you may be surprised that such a flight was an achievement so recently
而如今，纽约直飞香港的航班已经很常见了
Nowadays, non-stop New York to Hong Kong flights are far from exceptional
每天有五架飞机载着上千名旅客在两个城市之间直飞
Five planes carrying more than 1,000 passengers total fly non-stop daily between the two cities
而且在今天这种航班根本挤不进世界最远程航班前20名
and nowadays, this route doesn’t even crack the list of the top 20 longest flights in the world
尤其是最近三年，这种超远程航班呈现一种急剧增长的趋势
Especially in the past three years, there’s been a noticeable and dramatic rise in the number of ultra-long haul flights
接下来列举最长直飞航班前十名，排在第十的是2009年开通的
Among the ten longest non-stop flights, the one on this list that’s existed the longest, since 2009
达美航空每日从约翰内
斯堡飞亚特兰大的航班
is Delta’s daily service from Johannesburg to Atlanta
左上是排名 右上是机型
左下是距离 中下是起降时间 右下是运营航司
这是美国的航司
唯一一个飞南非的航班
—the only flight by an American airline to South Africa
在2016年，美联航开始
从旧金山直飞新加坡
In 2016 United started non-stop flights between San Francisco and Singapore
终结了两个国家之间
没有直飞航班的一段时间
—ending an era during which there were no non-stop connections between the two countries
在2018年10月，菲律宾航空开始
用新买的A350从马尼拉直飞纽约
Just recently in October, 2018 Philippine Airlines began flying from Manila to New York non-stop on their new A350
2014年，澳大利亚航空
推出悉尼直飞达拉斯的航班
In 2014, Qantas starting flying non-stop in both directions from Sydney to Dallas
成为在当时
世界上最远程的航班
—then the longest flight in the world
在2018年年初美联航增加了
休斯顿直飞悉尼的航班
In early 2018 United added another connection to down under with their route from Houston to Sydney
新加坡航空在2018年11月
添加另一个飞美国洛杉矶的航班
Singapore Airlines added another US connection in November 2018 flying to Los Angeles
阿联酋航空从2016年开始执飞
A380机型的最远航线——迪拜到奥克兰
and Emirates has operated the longest nonstop A380 flight in the world from Dubai to Auckland since 2016
澳航在2018年3月开启
首个澳洲到欧洲的直飞航班
Qantas started the first and currently only non-stop connection between Australia and Europe in March, 2018
执飞机型为787-9，
从珀斯飞到伦敦
with their daily dreamliner service from Perth to London
卡塔尔航空有到前不久为止
最长的航班——多哈到奥克兰
and Qatar operates what was until recently the longest non-stop flight from Doha all the way to Auckland
而全世界航程最远的航班，
超过了第二名五百英里
Lastly, the longest flight in the world, confidently beating the runner up by over 500 miles
是新加坡航空的每天从
新加坡飞纽约纽瓦克机场的航班
is the newly launched daily Singapore Airlines flight between Singapore and Newark
距离9534英里(15343公里)，
飞行时间因风而定最多19小时
clocking in at 9,534 miles and up to 19 hours of flight time depending on winds
这十个航班里有八个是最近三年开通的
Eight of the ten flights on this list were launched in the past three years
虽然可以理解为随着科技发展飞机能飞的更远了
While it can be expected that as technology advances airplane range will get longer
但这种地球上远距离城市之间直飞航班的增长趋势是很明显的
there’s been a noticeable acceleration in the addition of non-stop routes between earth’s furthest city pairs
就像各种现象一样，有成因也有影响
Like any phenomenon, this has causes and effects
驱使超远程航班出现的一个原因
One factor driving this surge in ultra-long haul flights
是过去十年内两款新飞机的诞生——A350和787
is the release of two new planes in the past decade—the A350 and 787
上述十个航班有六个由这两种飞机执飞
Six of the ten longest routes are flown by one of these two planes
之前也出现过能飞这种距离的飞机，但它们经济性太差
Now, planes have existed before that could fly the routes these fly but they weren’t as economical
新加坡航空在2004年到2014年曾经使用A340
Singapore Airlines previously flew the world’s longest flight from Singapore to Newark from 2004 until 2014 on the A340
执飞新加坡到纽瓦克航班，是当时世界上距离最远的航班
但A340的高油耗让他们在油价上涨的时候不得不取消这条线路
but its high fuel consumption forced them to cancel the route as soon as oil prices ticked up
A340运力不如A350，航程不如A350，油耗却比A350高35%
To fly fewer passengers a shorter maximum distance, an A340 uses 35% more fuel than the A350
对于这些世界级超远程航班，经济效益就是一切
Economics is everything with the world’s longest routes
因为从新加坡直飞纽约的航班燃油消耗要比
The truth is that flying a non-stop flight from Singapore to New York uses more fuel
新加坡飞东京再飞纽约的经停航班多
than flying a stopping service from Singapore to Tokyo to New York
这听上去可能有点反直觉，因为飞机起降时耗油比巡航时多得多
Now, this might seem counterintuitive since planes use far more fuel per minute taking off than they do in cruise
而直飞航班只要一次起飞，而不是两次
and flying nonstop requires one take off instead of two
但你们忘了，携带大量燃料飞行需要消耗额外的燃料
but that's failing to consider that it uses fuel to carry fuel
以777-200为例，飞行800海里
的航班，平均每英里耗油30.6磅
With a 777-200, for example, flying 800 nautical miles will use about 30.6 pounds of fuel per mile
“平均每英里油耗(磅)”数值在航程
增加到3000海里中不断下降
That pounds per mile average decreases up until reaching a total flight distance of about 3,000 nautical miles
而超过3000海里后，该数值又
会增加，直到航程上限8000海里
Beyond that, the pound per mile figure increases up until 8,000 nautical miles
在8000海里时，飞机
平均每英里油耗32.2磅
where the aircraft would burn 32.2 pounds of fuel per mile flown
这是因为到了最后，携带大量燃料远程飞行所需的额外燃料
This is because eventually, the added burn from flying the extra fuel needed to fly long distance
已经超过了起飞所需的额外燃料了
overtakes the extra fuel used to take off
这意味着使用这种飞机
That means that, with this aircraft
本来卡塔尔航空用它从多哈直飞休斯顿的8000英里
which is used to fly the daily 8,000 mile Qatar flight between Doha and Houston
却不如经停飞行更加节省燃料，比如从多哈先飞巴黎
it would be more efficient on a fuel consumption basis to fly something like Doha to Paris
然后巴黎飞哈利法克斯，再从哈利法克斯飞休斯顿
Paris to Halifax, and Halifax to Houston rather than flying the whole trip in one go
这也是货运航空极少飞超远程航线的原因之一
This is part of the reason why cargo airlines rarely fly ultra-long haul routes
尽管UPS有足够多的的货物去支持路易斯维尔到香港的直飞航线
While UPS has plenty enough cargo to support a non-stop flight between their Louisville and Hong Kong hubs
机型也能做到直飞，他们还是会经停安克雷奇，部分原因就是省油
and the aircraft that could fly it in one go, they fly the route with a stop in Anchorage partially for fuel saving reasons
当然，飞机停留多了会影响飞机多拉快跑多赚钱
Of course, any time on the ground is time that an aircraft could be in the air making money
这对节省下油钱的削弱也是货航不会只飞3000英里就经停的部分原因
so that degrades the savings and that’s part of why cargo airlines don’t only fly in 3,000 mile hops
时间对货航固然重要，但对民航更加重要
Time matters for cargo airlines but not nearly as much as it does for passenger airlines
民航拉的是人
Passenger airlines have to deal with people
人比快递对多出来的几个小时旅行时间更加敏感
which are far more sensitive to a few extra hours of travel time than boxes
直飞航班尤其对于商务旅客来讲需求很高
Non-stop flights are typically more desirable especially to the business traveller
这也是为什么航司会把过站航班定价高于直飞航班
which is why airlines will price connecting itineraries typically higher than non-stop ones
无论多短的航线，航司运营过站航班的成本也要比直飞航班高
even on short routes where the cost to the airline of operating a connecting itinerary is higher than that of a non-stop flight
因为过站的成本高，航司才会开始考虑运营直飞航班而不是过站航班
With higher costs, airlines therefore need to justify operating non-stop flights instead of stopping ones
新加坡航空还用更大的A380执飞新加坡过站法兰克福到纽约的航班
Singapore airlines does operate another flight to New York via Frankfurt with a far larger A380
但直飞航班主要还是面对能付更多钱的商务旅客
but the non-stop flight is primarily operated to appeal to the business traveller who can pay more
一般能够运营超远程航班的两个城市都有很多的商务往来
Often, the routes with enough demand to support ultra long-haul flights are the ones with high business traffic
比如悉尼、新加坡、香港、纽约这样比较富有的大城市
between big, wealthy cities like Sydney, Singapore, Hong Kong, London, and New York
即使是世界著名旅游胜地夏威夷
Even though Hawaii, for example, is one of the top vacation destinations in the world
你也找不到几个从那直飞伦敦的远程航班
you just don’t see many long-haul flights to it from places like London
因为去旅游的人对价格很敏感
because leisure travelers are more sensitive to price
他们愿意花更少钱在洛杉矶转机而不是花更多钱从伦敦直飞
and they’d rather pay less to fly via Los Angeles rather than on a non-stop from London for more
也因此，新加坡航空用于飞纽瓦克机场的A350上
For this reason, on the A350’s Singapore Airlines uses to fly to Newark
根本没有那种旅游的乘客经常会订的经济舱座位
they didn’t even bother including an economy class, the kind that leisure travelers tend to book
而是只有高级经济舱和商务舱
They only have premium economy and business class
更少的座位、更少的乘客、更少的行李，就是更少的重量
With the lower weight from fewer bags, seats, and passengers
飞机可以更加高效地飞往地球另一边
the plane can fly more efficiently to the other side of the world
并且从航司角度来看，他们也没损失太多
and, from the airlines perspective, they’re not loosing out on much
毕竟要是卖经济舱的话票价就要低得有竞争力，更赚不到多少钱
since, at the prices they would have to sell economy seats at to be competitive, they really wouldn’t be making much money anyways
高级舱位的高利润让他们即使在这种超远程航班中也能赚到不少钱
The higher margins of premium classes give them a better shot of breaking even on this flight
当然，超远程航班爆发的另一个因素是油价的降低
Of course, the other factor contributing to the rise of these ultra-long haul flights is the low cost of fuel
航空燃油的价格在2015年减半，
并在2016年1月以每加仑85美分触底
Jet fuel prices halved in 2015 and bottomed out at a cost of only 85 cents per gallon in January 2016
之后油价又温和增长，导致人们
开始质疑航空业是否进入了寒冬
Since then prices have steadily risen leading some to question whether troubled times were ahead for the industry
但2018年10月油价又跌了
but prices again took a dive in October 2018
反正总的来说，过去四年，油价的确比以前便宜不少
Overall, over the past four years, prices are lower than ever
而油价降低带来航司成本降低，使得远程航班成本有所降低
and with that fuel represents a smaller proportion of an airline’s cost so it’s proportionally cheaper to fly longer distances
这种油价的波动带来了一些航司的崛起
This fluctuation in fuel cost has also contributed to the rise
也导致一些类似Norwegian、Wow和Primra等长途廉价航空的衰落
and in some cases fall, of long haul budget airlines such as Norwegian Airlines, Wow Air, and Primera Air
所以我们理清了超远程航班雨后春笋般涌现的原因
So we’ve established the causes of this proliferation of ultra-long flights
但它的影响是什么？
but what are its effects?
往返澳洲、新西兰与欧洲的航线是最繁忙的远程航线之一
One of the busiest long distance flows of passengers is from Europe to Australia and New Zealand and vice versa
两地的文化类似，又有频繁的商业往来
As two areas with close cultural and business connections
尽管单程要花24小时，但还是有很多人往返两地
plenty of people travel between them despite it taking about 24 hours each way
在上世纪几乎每个飞往澳洲的欧洲大航司都会中途经停某处
Before the turn of the century almost every major European Airline flew to Australia via some stopping point
如法航、荷航、汉莎、意大利航、英航会经停曼谷、新加坡或者香港
like Bangkok, Singapore, or Hong Kong including Air France, KLM, Lufthansa, Alitalia, and British Airways
有些每天还有多个航班
—some with multiple daily flights
而今天，只有一个欧洲航司的一个航班飞往澳洲
Today, though, there is only one sole flight by a European Airlines to Australia
那就是英航，每天一班伦敦飞悉尼，过站新加坡
—British Airways’ once daily flight from London to Singapore to Sydney
同时，澳航、纽航也是各自国家唯一一个有飞往欧洲航班的航司
Meanwhile, Qantas is the only Australian Airline and Air New Zealand the only Kiwi airline
to operate services all the way to Europe
两边的航司们都损失了中间亚洲航空公司的市场份额
All the airlines on each end have lost market share to those in between—the Asian airlines
过去几十年像阿联酋和新加坡航这样的航司
In the past few decades airlines like Emirates and Singapore Airlines
成为了人们在两地之间旅行最受欢迎的选择
have become the most popular for those traveling between the two areas as
因为如果你要是坐英航，那你就必须从悉尼起飞，最终只能到达伦敦
if you were to fly British Airways you would have to start in Sydney and end in London
但如果选阿航，你可以从澳洲或新西兰里六个直飞迪拜的城市出发
Flying on Emirates, on the other hand, you can start at any of their six non-stop destinations in Australia and New Zealand
到了迪拜只转机一次，就能飞往欧洲数十个城市了
connect via Dubai, and end up at any of their dozens of European destinations with one stop
这样更快，也通常更便宜，因此英航每周只有7班飞澳洲
It’s just faster and often cheaper and so, while British Airways operates seven weekly flights to Australia
而阿航有84班，新加坡航有137班
Emirates operates 84 and Singapore 137
不止阿航和新航，还有国泰、阿提哈德、卡塔尔航空
Both of these airlines and more including Cathay Pacific, Etihad, and Qatar Airways
也都成为了运营欧洲飞澳洲航班的能手
have become experts in operating connecting flights between Europe and Australasia
但他们能做到此事的原因是这段旅途你无论如何都要转机或过站
But the reason they’re able to do this is because you have to stop on these routes anyways
因为这个距离太远了，无法直飞，至少以前是这样
—it’s too far for non-stop flights, or rather, it used to be
2018年3月起，开头说的第三名，澳航开通了珀斯飞伦敦的直飞航班
Since March, 2018, number three on that list of longest flights is Qantas’ new non-stop flight from Perth to London
很多人怀疑会不会仍然有很多旅客青睐转机一次的选择
Many were skeptical when this flight launched that customers would prefer it to a one-stop option
那样更便宜、还能半路歇歇伸伸腿，但最终数据显示恰恰相反
where they could pay less and stretch their legs halfway through their trip but the data proves otherwise
自从该航班开通，其上座位卖出了92%
Since launch, 92% of available seats on this route have been sold
这是一个相当不错的客座率
This is an exceptionally good load factor, as its called
因为澳航国际航班的平均客座率只有84%
as Qantas’ average load factor for international flights is only 84%
澳航也因此开始考虑继续开通其他珀斯直飞巴黎、法兰克福的欧洲航班
For this reason Qantas is strongly considering launching other non-stop European routes from Perth to Paris and Frankfurt
而其它航司也着手准备开通新的欧洲飞澳洲的直飞航班
In addition, other airlines are looking at starting new non-stop routes from Europe to Australia
维珍大西洋航空创始人理查德·布兰森说过
Founder Richard Branson has said that
维珍大西洋航空正着手准备“尽快”开通伦敦到珀斯的直飞航班
Virgin Atlantic is looking to start non-stop flights from London to Perth, “as soon as possible.”
位于伊斯坦布尔的土耳其航空，是一个欧洲的航司
Turkish Airlines, based in Istanbul, is technically still a European Airline
虽然就离亚欧的边界几英里
even if it’s just miles from the border with Asia
而该航空将成为了第一个欧洲直飞悉尼的航空公司
and it’s set to become to first airline to start flying non-stop from Europe to Sydney
前提是其按照公布的计划，在2019年使用新买的787执飞此航班
if it follows through with its announced plans to launch these flights in 2019 with its new 787 dreamliners
澳航每日一班就已经对亚洲的那些航司利润有影响了
While the once daily Qantas flight is doing little to cut into the Asian carrier’s profits right now
如果越来越多的航班不经停亚洲的中转机场
if more and more flights start bypassing the Asian hubs
那原本连接澳洲与欧洲的亚洲航空公司就会损失一大部分利润
the major connecting airlines could be given a run for their money
与此同时，一场比赛也悄然打响，谁能最先开通可能是最有价值的
Meanwhile, the race is on to see who will start flying what is perhaps the most valuable route in the world
之前从未有过直飞的线路，比如悉尼到伦敦
that doesn’t yet have a non-stop connection—Sydney to London
澳航将首先得到这个机会
Chances are the first will be Qantas
多年以前，澳航就向飞机制造商波音、空客提出需求
A number of years ago, Qantas challenged aircraft manufacturers Boeing and Airbus
让他们造出能从悉尼满载出发、不间断飞行21小时直飞伦敦的飞机
to create a plane that could fly the 21 hour non-stop flight fully loaded all the way to London
制造商那边很快就要交付了，而澳航说他们要在
The manufacturers are close to delivering and Qantas has said they will make their decision
空客A350-1000ULR与波音777-8之间做出选择，2019年底给答复
between the Airbus A350-1000ULR or Boeing 777-8 by the end of 2019
航班可能会在2022年或2023年开通，到时候就不止是悉尼飞伦敦了
From there, flights would start in 2022 or 2023 not only on the Sydney to London route
还可能是墨尔本或者布里斯班飞纽约或巴黎
but also potentially from Melbourne and Brisbane and to New York and Paris
作为澳大利亚人的首选航空公司
Being the airline of choice for Australians
恐怕全世界没有谁能像澳航那样驾驭21小时直飞的超远程航班了
perhaps no airline globally has a better shot at making a 21 hour non-stop flight work than Qantas
随着最新机型的交付，飞机可以连续飞行11000英里(17000公里)
With the arrival of the newest set of planes, airlines can now fly as far as 11,000 miles non-stop
这意味着地球上几乎任意两个大人口城市都能直飞
That means that nearly every populated point on earth can feasibly be connected by non-stop flights
随着科技的不断进步，估计不久地球上任意两点都能做到直飞了
With more technological advancements on their way, absolutely every point on earth will soon be reachable non-stop
这说明，限制超远程航班发展的唯一阻碍
What that means is that the only factors now restricting the development of ultra-long haul flights
是经济性，而不是技术难度
are economic, not technological
在许多方面，关于超远程航班的增长趋势问题的答案
In many ways, the question of whether this trend of the proliferation of ultra-long haul flight
都和燃油价格有关
is up to the mercy of fuel prices
如果油价持续走低，那就会有越来越多的18、19甚至20小时的航班
If they stay low, we’ll have more and more 18, 19, or 20 hour flights
但如果涨了，你放心吧航司肯定会取消这些航班的
while if they go up, you can be sure that airlines will cancel these routes in droves
飞机虽然速度没有变快，但利用直飞缩短了旅途时间
While the planes are not flying any faster, they’re getting passengers to their destination in less time
所以这些新的直飞到地球另一边的航班
so these new non-stop routes to the other side of the world
正在帮助拉近彼此的距离，让世界越来越小
are helping to make the world just a little bit smaller, one flight at a time
字幕翻译给虫，欢迎点赞投币收藏转发分享评论关注充电~
以下仍然是恰饭时间
If you have an idea for a business, whether it be just you as a freelancer or the next Fortune 500 company
one of the first steps in making an idea reality is setting up a website
No matter what you do, it’s crucial in this century to have a website and Squarespace
helps you set up a site in as little as minutes for a reasonable monthly price
Their website builder is simple to use and the customizable designer templates make it
nearly impossible to create a bad-looking website
Squarespace also has excellent, award-winning 24/7 customer support in case you need help
They handle all the behind the scenes so you don’t have to code upgrade, or patch your website ever
Get started building your corner of the internet today by signing up for a free-trial at squarespace.com/Wendover
and then, when you’re ready to launch, that same link will get you 10% off
and you’ll be supporting the show while you’re at it
Also, on my other channel, Half as Interesting, I just released a video on the longest duration
non-stop flight to ever exist—the 32 hour flight Qantas flew from Perth to Sri Lanka
during WWII in order to reconnect the empire
Click the annotation on-screen to check that out and I’ll see you again in two weeks
with another Wendover Productions video